...so that's just the usual reminder
will come back to that at the end I just want to very quickly
...the frame streaming is such a very kind of commonly used
term these days so I just...quickly set the...of mind
wrong what we're referring to here for many of you this will likely be totally obvious
suggesting case so, when we talk about data address
in a traditional way one simple picture is it's just causing the parking lot and if you
want to ask questions like how many read cars are the parking lot
...like asking database question we scan the parking lots maybe with...index and we
count the cars right with data in motion casket flying by on
the freeway diverging them to a parking lot in order to count them would be the approach
of capturing streaming data into some archive and then running batch
...over them what we wanted to talk about here is processing data
in motion while its flying through the system okay so it's all about, for example,
counting the right...answer drive-by and the question how many can
broadcast growth by doesn't even have an answer unless you also
say within the last ten minutes right because the question
nominee castro phi phone infinite sequence of
...will actually never return?
Before we divx into how this various,
various things...build one to do a first the little
demo we have worked from really our private previous stage on with
...swedish medical device manufacture errol crime and
their claim to fame is device looks a little bit we sometimes
...use it looks like a breathalyzer it actually is a breathalyzer
doesn't look for alcohol it looks from nitric oxide and it turns out if you do it
exactly right it is an excellent early
detectfor the kind of appending asthma attack so, as
...you can actually use this device to find just the right time
to take steroids or to avoid taking steroids which have their own problems so,
that's what they do and they wanted to move beyond building
their devices and in particular I wanted to move to a point
...devices can be run in practices or even
in homes where people have possibly, possibly no training for proper
use so let's just look at how this device acts
sure so, I?
A patient will usually
hold this mouthpiece and the process of running an experiment is first to inhale
the here and then you breed out into the device and the process takes approximately twenty.
Seconds there are some sensors inside the device and...crane
...the hospitals we use them to be in a certain environment condition to maintain
...environment conditions for this to work
property sometimes they are not and the device calibration...go wrong the
...doesn't even know when they're trying it out so now after this gets hooked up in
a realtime system they can easily alert the hospitals that hey this
...device needs calibration or your temperature conditions has changed so
let's see how this real-time nature will look like I...try to run an experiment
and this particular chart a shows the humidity coming from a
sensor inside this device it also tells me the temperature and when I
inhale and xcel that creates a pressure that can also be shown in the map?
...tiny...start the application this
device gets connected to this laptop or any pc and using
...application it will transfer the data to the cloud.
So, what we're seeing here is the pressure change during inhale pressure drop during
exhale pressure roles now the device will take about a minutes to come up with
some diagnostic results and what error cry and really wants to do is not
just monitor one such device remotely that may be interesting for a physician
...they really care about...monitoring all the plot devices today in the...with
ambitions to go way beyond that centrally so they can look for various
opportunities like reaching out for support...delivering a new
biochemical sensor that is about to reach its end-of-life?
So, at this point I think we can go back to the.
Actual deck and.
Step back a little bit sorry
rank round-up thrown back we just saw is
a scenario of connecting devices that historically where you
...not only weakly connected to meet some sort of
larger business demand and
...a whole collection of scenarios that we have looked at with various public
companies the two things I want to quickly drill into here...real-time
...detection and what he has called smart grit as two different examples
the first one is actually fairly generic thing we have seen
...whether interested in looking at atm that show,
for example, a strange withdrawal pattern where just before midnight and
just after midnight the maximum allowable amount this withdrawn and they would like to use
that to immediately trigger and alert likewise and by the way this
isn't always fraught but is very calmly correlate with fraude then another
case would be click fraught in advertising systems various forms of
fraught in online gaming systems so on so there's a whole world of trying to
look for anomalies that indicate fraudulent use the smart great
cases quite different and you actually saw it mentioned in the key notes the
...smart guys from sweden talked about that this morning as well
the idea here is to go and say by having
all my devices in the field connected to the klout I can
look for various opportunities like preventative maintenance so in the smart
...case I may want to goal and rewrote our
through different branch in the system if, for example,
a correlation between...prediction and weather forecast suggests
there's a huge opportunity for an outage based on the current ourtransmission lines
...chosen by the system right so there's a number of things you can do
...stepping out of the system looking at a lot of
data correlating it with contextual data like whether data so, with that?
I would actually like to welcome richard mccormick onstage
who ...of sales and marketing...to america and we'll talk about a
really exciting application that you might not see coming is not connected
...thank you...thank you?
...ever some people a probably so connected...this morning I will put that in context
...they got
...some other good ec...we're going to put...but it right there we go which is fine.
So, we worked with microsoft over the last few years
on a specific proof of concept around the production
of lattice I'll show you that in just a little while this is part of a total
...to solution known as...access...a one-stop-shop information
communication solution in the food and agriculture area we've been doing production management
control greenhouse work which is where the lettuce comes from a full remote-sensing network
...out there and then animal has been requirements that's where the connected
...story came from this morning if you didn't hear the story in the area
of animal husband has been very when the lady can within the mood
as they say we can detect that through a cow predominant hooked up to
...as...cloud and then work it out but, I think...killer job on that this morning so we don't need to we don't
...it to repeat that story he took all the glory of connected
cow me-let me left me with lettuce so I needed
to give about that story of the...the meet I get the
...that's fine so what we actually do.
The probably the best way to show you how the
...is farmed and where it comes from is to jump straight away to a little video we actually
go live into the factory and then I'll describe in words...tradeoff with but...if you can
play the video just a minute-and-a-half long also that should be just great?
...actually on the audio...
All right so we probably should every...that aspect.
The...or I can I can talk to it that aren't so what the
...tree is saying is we've connected up the factory to a set of
sensors and here the technicians working on that factories in the
...a prefix...of japan itself format semi-conductor factory
...semiconductor factory has a clean room we've taken that clean room environment changed it
from producing chips to producing lattice and you may say why would
an electronics company like fidget to wish to be producing
lattice the reason is that people with kidney is use need
low potassium foods to help themselves...low potassium foods
all our can be a gained by boiling the food so if
you stabbing boiled brussel sprouts boiled potatoes and things like that you'll be just
...potassium diet pone something crunchy if you want something a bit more role
low potassium diet is perhaps not the way for you to go so what we've done we worked with a number of
universities and worked out how to gain all how to manufacture how to grow
low potassium lettuce it's more expensive than standard
lattice of course but, if you're in an environment where you can't
eat lattice normally or other current to products and this is a little bit of a
...improvement for-you the application...running on the screen I can just see
...about measures a number of different parameters I'll tell you about that when I show you the app because I've got it
running lies on a pc here?
I think it's about so I can move on...cool actually...that's a good
...the product itself when it comes out get shipped in standard bags like this
woman actually shipped in
last friday from japan because it took quite a while to get here from japan
...itself inside wasn't particularly good and anyway the fda told me they didn't appreciate me bringing
...infant japan without a proper license so in fact they
ship an empty bag this morning and I went to my good local organic...
american lattice in the...delicious as?
So, if anyone...which can I try that low potassium lettuce
...you have to trust make this is exactly what it looks like but it's
kinda fun to have a logo on the front...that is there the best part of the packaging no
...the back bunch of japanese current...course describing lettuce and then it says size
...I'll never do for the american market we need xcel or maybe
...ledges if we're going to oscillate in this market but it's
...is not being produced as I said from a size point of view
all taste point of view that is interesting the real key thing that's of course the
low potassium count in that so how do we do this let me show you the if you go into the next slide
...I grab my little pc here and you really caught me out by making me do the
voice-over on that one that was not very fair...that's okay thank you for jumping
...we can do...bring up the app so the app itself
which the technicians have in the factory has a number of different parameters on it
it's monitoring in the factory temperature monitoring humidity levels
...of course a conduct that's a celebrity
measure in desi siemens the ph level and the temperature of the
broth itself they produce the lattice basically hydra
...so it has fluids grown if you want to produce
lettuce in a known and very carefully controlled environment you can't just planted in the ground amount
of how carefully you monitor the ground and you take care of it things get into it so it's produced in the
clean room under the control of hydra
...with complete control of the environment first innovation
wave we did at the access high plant factory as I said in focus fema resulted
enough's producing physically the lettuce but we had variations...production
...were variations in batches that will variations in the time of when we could do things
we streaming a huge amount of data back from
the tool itself we didn't know and didn't see how we could correlating work between
those things hence we call that good friends at microsoft and the second-round?
Actually move the data into the as you cloud and move the data analysis into
...biif and our view so let's move on to that next slide please clements.
So, we're not finished their...moving forward left some of the that might nice japanese translation
in here provide foods with pleasure that means.
...right that's on the slide what that basically means is not just
not only expanding the number of different products that are made with low potassium that into a improve
the taste maybe you will want to buy my relatively expensive lattice just for the flavor
it in your...but that was not the goal the goal of courses...control and
an optimizing the environment it's right...focus...which is in to whoo-hoo
a region of japan that's the region...the earthquake if you recall what two years ago
brian something like that so it's part of...in that region so using a this effort to
advance agriculture in that part of the world and,
of course we're improving our business and doing proof of concept around
ict concepts keep going clements you can go button that...
a great here's what the factory concept looks like in terms visualization we've got a
...dashboard we've built...executive level a management level and,
operational level what-you...on the...windows forget to windows tablet I just showed
is like a mock-up of it let's jump into the actual if you can go and play the video
of the actual design itself it looks fantastic we just
won an award at the if design conference for the design itself and...
to all we'll talk you through this one once clinton plays...I put my pc on top of your.
...go so here's the...interface in this case it's actually an environmental
monitoring interface into the tool the japanese language you'll be able to understand some of the city
names in a minute you can cs looking for trouble when there's trouble going on in the
world...trouble...going to come up in red here we can see something happening
around our facility in japan I think the operate is going to zoom in and just a
second into the different into this specific region of japan and there is
to city achiever running at a hundred and ten percent of whatever the thing is it's measuring at
that point where could that problem bates right there in this particular factory so we've done
...zoom in now to factory level we spotted what's going on inside the fact
...that particular production line you've now got a monitor showing you exactly what's going
wrong on that production line I think now it's actually going to even say there's the specific device
there's a piece of equipment which is going wrong the interface therefore is built
in a very beautiful way to look like that's going to plaintiff it'll go clemens
...keep going...a gap for me to get...back...
They're now yet with a good gap...so now we move to a different part of the demonstration not quite
so visually appealing but here we go looking at a number of different samples this data is
life data from focus...so if you look at the little
...stuff on the left and right that's not a powerpoint issue or even...ten problem the
guys actually gone and rubbed out the data that he didn't want this information going out but what they're
doing is looking at quality management here looking at the different some
...batches in the post planting environment ie the...has been planted let's
...as it goes along and now we're going to actually look at three
different environment variables we just change the name to be environment ab and c instead of saying
actually what it was in terms of be this...nato ph level or temperature
...what's been happening at those different environmental variables over I think this
is a six-month period in the middle of last year and then go into
correlation this was where the benefit came of...view and the streaming analytics to allow
us to actually correlate data even though I'm not a farmer I'm definitely normal
farmers can't really understand the difference between these different a...so we wanted to use machine
learning and use the computer side of things to actually try and help us out so what we're doing here is
choosing a date range and then drilling into some details of the correlation
between the tools and I think the guy's going to japanese button for a play in just a minute to actually
them play and look for the correlation between these variables over this time period and
that...just click...for those of...that can speak japanese
was play media time stream and I think down the bottom of the screen it'll now
...along...show you the correlation between the various data factors that is found
...egos...now at the very end.
So, in this way we're able to drill
down and find more detailed information jump up to my next slide...if you can.
So, here's what the as you a ...next one after that please
comments and again there we go here's what the system landscape
looks like you can see where using a full as your environment we hooked upwith
event helps we've got I at platform on the left in the factory coming through as
...with the different event hubs into the management dashboard which I just showed you a little example
of we can also of course put the information to office three sixty five if we need to
aswell same time keep going on to my next...clements...just conscious of
your time so we can get through this so lessons learned from the whole proof of concept number one.
You can buy it it's on sailed
...not this one of course this came from a local organic farmer but bags like this full
of delicious lattice if you're in japan it's proven to be a concept that
...we found...we work together often innovation point of view you have to choose you write
...together...to a microsoft working together
but you need that support of your end-user customer extremely important we found
as we work with the end-users with the farmers in the factory they
were most interested in focusing on the apps the...apps themselves they didn't so much
care about what was happening in the back-end in the cloud or what was happening out there in the
it section they with the farmers and they wanted to learn how to use the data that's where I think we
sold the real our of the as you analytics?
Thank you microsoft thank you richard thank you for...to bank the overall.
All right and because it's so much fun to look
at what other people do with your technology we now have taught and
...talk to us about the project that actually had quite a few
...over the time and the think you can talk about that ...is an architect
for the microsoft technology sentence which some of you may know they have locations
in many cities and help anyone who wants to use kind-of are leading bleeding edge
technologies to build solutions and they half a number of samples solutions and
demonstrate us so it's kind of fun place to go to as well.
Thank you...so good afternoon so,
project inception it's got a cool name probably not as cool as the growing the
lettuce thing but we doing some cool stuff how many have you have been down to
the connect booth downstairs and saw the target cosmetics
demos write a few view if you have
...after we get done you're going to want to gaussian all right inception
is a project that was created sort of collaboratively
between microsoft and target and in candidly it was actually
a larger project and even that...one of the things that I find.
A challenging is I've been in this industry for
awhile and I'm still not thrilled with how computers work
all right I candidly the way we interact with technology the way we use tablets
and devices essentially their mainframes and really small suits all right I
want I want tony stark okay I want jarvis...is what I'm
gone and for I want the ability to create
ambient intelligence the ability to engage you on your terms doing what you
want to do and target wanted to do the same thing they wanted
...experience that actually understood what the consumer
guest was doing and reacted in modified
to them based on what was happening the intent is to make it almost magical
...the leverage what they already have in a form of infrastructure
in the ultimately understand the user's
intent the other key thing is well I can certainly gorton point you at some really
tiller msr videos with like really cool interactions right and I
want to build those I only get three weeks and I don't have a ph-d in mathematics
all right what's amazing is the technology that the folks in as
your stream analytics and as your overall and some of the
sensor technology is coming to bear that allows pretty
traditional developers to push the envelope to really change the way people
experience technology inception I hope proves that out what.
So, what I'm going to demonstrate is a reference that we
build so inception was built as we said initially
collaboratively with target and what we wanted to do is understand where the people were engaging as they were
coming up to the environment to the fixture to whatever that was so we were able to
define different zones of interactivity based on what they're doing or delivering content
pulling that for measure and then streaming the telemetry live into the
cloud so that we can gain insight into what's happening and then ultimately learn
...react to things that might be going on a band people are hanging out they're,
they're looking?
Puzzled...like reach out and help them those are the kinds of things we
wanted to do and what you see there are also from the connect sensors a...over
to any see when after we got done working with target any see approach this and said,
you know, what we can do even more cool things if we combine your connect
sensor with our anonymous biometric services to be able to understand
age engender and then even in secures scenarios be able to understand who the user is
individually there's some really interesting interactions that you can start to drive that way?
So, ultimately we can-we can at this point perhaps draw a line to the how
all dot net that we saw this morning and that went by
the way realistically viral on twitter right now right but, it is still very interesting to see what
we're seeing here is even a step beyond that you're not submitting of photo
nt waiting a second or something this is all happening right there right there
in real-time a that, you know, reaching out to the cloud to
perform that function while interesting when you're trying to interact with somebody that's
present right now that delay could cause a problem so leveraging
any see sort of industrial service on the client within
a tenth of a second to get that information is a whole lot more reactive experience than
waiting I mean hopefully the
...fast but god knows what's happening and it could be two minutes and suddenly they
left all right so now all of it is foundation only built on top of the
microsoft stack from the connect sensor right through to the code
that's executing on the device that's all csharp code ultimately delivering that up
to as your the event hub being process through asa then ultimately in the
...five and then to a big data cluster and ultimately can be fit into machine learning
ultimately we can party on that data
and excel and that's cool but you know, that too much talk legal the next slide.
So, inception is really again I...mention it about
it's about transparent...it's about a collaboration as
what are the things that the technology centers do is we like to do the hard stuff come to
us and say we want this magical thing where like yap game on let's try that
of having partners like any see who like stepped up and
...let's try this and started the builder tools and extend their tools and such a way that we
could consume them and new in interesting ways and then finally what really
blew the doors off of target.
Was the fact that we did in three weeks.
They were like wow that is like ridiculously fast and it's a case of, you know,
what when, you know,
your kung fu all right you can really execute having the cloud is the backbone and the
sensors all right so let's do a demonstration so...connect
...flying all over the room absolutely read connect...flying we had yacht
...toxic walks it does amazing things so what you see up there is the
kiosk that is actually here that was live in the store but if I can
get switched over to which one is this five-point-five art?
So, groovy what I'm going to do here is I can actually run code if you really
want to go to code but I think what we'll do is I'm going-to go ahead and run
the inception executable here and...awesome,
awesome a is that a compelling user experience or what okay man that is awesome
...shoppers just gravitate to that kind of experience well what
you're seeing here is the experience understands not only people everybody knows
...connect...track and I can play games and stuff but what they don't realize is that we can
...to understand objects in a physical space this is the calibration window that we use
to actually teach it where objects are in a physical space I just thought it was geeky
funder show it off the black thing that you're seeing the black screen on the on the
far right-hand side of the display is actually showing where the physical item is
in three-dimensional space so you can think
...connect sensors at the top of the screen and you're seeing my body here's this...line
if I move my hand seo my hands are out there that's actually showing the depth range
to my hands but we're not going to calibrate we're just going to go in and try some stuff so remember I
talked to-you about having it have the ability to understand when somebody is in a
certain space right so there's different ranges that interactive I've
defined for this case it doesn't need for it could have
won so passive engages delivering some content I
...in closer it goes into active attract this content can be whatever you
wanted to be now at this point the any see tools are biometric
...sampling my face doing an agent gender
analysis to additionally target content if we wanted to now if I walk
up even further they think I'm starting to play with it and then when I walk up on top of it I
...active engage mode which means it's assuming up
...here picking up things on playing with stuff and it wants to help
error go the high piece all right so right now it's monitoring
in its watching what I'm doing now what's fun is this is only half the
show if I flip over here too?
To asher I'm in the...one of the stream analytics pipelines that we use this is
a relatively stripped down query that we're using so one of the things that you might
want to do is hey I think I mention the fact that somebody might be shopping
too long hours hanging out or looks like puzzle
...well this is a this is an interesting tumbling time window query
that is actually looking at the tracking data that we're
sending from connect we're sending every frame I mean every excuse
me every third frame from connect up to the as your cloud so that we can
tell you in three-dimensional space what was happening I can have services like asa
monitor those things and understand that while there seems to be something going
amiss let-me...push notification to you...a few moments here all cross
that threshold and app on my band will buzz me and say somebody needs help
...the kiosks you want to go over and talk to them that's cool right
okay now.
We have got all of that now what's even more fun is let's go
party on some data all right so we've got a variety all here I
gotta go to that spreadsheet this one's more fun...go here there we go beer.
Okay,
...so this one is fun because guess what
we used inception at the super bowl it manage the bar
comment that's cool right so it actually watch beer bottles
...all...top all year getting goose...goose or whatever
or a blood-like and...keeping statistics over time and I've got this beautiful
our biif that allows me to look at hey there's a lot of old people are
sorry did I say that I'm sorry I'm in that age group to anyway, and,
what beverage where they selecting...edge people well aged absolutely,
absolutely experience folks are right and you might go why at the
super ball at the bar where the people skewed towards the fifty sixty age
bracket...was because the bar was the vip bar for all the
distributors all right so you can imagine they are a little more...and
than the average visitor so that's kind of fun so I can actually see which beer they selected
or by the way of one of the fundings we did with them is any see also
gave us access to their face recognition api now we didn't know anybody and
api doesn't know anybody all they wanted though
...anheuser wanted us to be able to do a personalize
...so basically when you walk up and you pick up a shock top
in leave and come back an hour later the sign says
page another shocked top?
All right take tony...man totally ok now let's go look at some other things.
...that when we are like that one let's look at ism so here's
trend telemetry trends over time so I can I don't have
as beautiful reports as my friends if would you too man I gotta get their graphic designer but
here I'm actually playing back over time where people were
in three-dimensional space that's really quick to show you but the numbers on
the protocol are meters away from the sensor and the bottom
numbers are indicating left and right in front of the device in this is sort of
an average over time where they were orbiting and relative position to the
sensor now if you think that's cool wait till you see I got a couple other reports to show you now we
hear we take the biometric data that any
see gave us and we third-party on that and we get the see by...
par by time what's different gender age...actually interacting with the environment
and then ultimately they do some interesting standard deviation stuff...and
...calculations that's all kind of cool now the one that I think
is the coolest visualization we have and I have to admit is a bit of a moon shot because I have
yet to see anybody do it and of course, come on,
big fella you can do this I know...tan...embarrass me now,
come on, I was going so well...here,
come on, come one come one.
...google movie that is not happiness...so I'm going to use the
...imagination here all right
after this if you come talk to me I'll show you the report all right.
What I was doing is any of you see our map before and excel
aura right we all see our map what is our map
new does geo mapping of telemetry data right I get to see sales
in different regions all that kind of stuff I bet you've never seen a our map that's
down to like half a meter?
I can actually play back and you can see people moving through
the space in front of the actual fixture I can see heat maps what product
their touching that is cool all right that...cool now especially if you
...yeah, absolutely, absolutely, absolutely I...it cool nonetheless it is
...cool nonetheless now so, we're collecting all this recapturing all this
were all punching up imagine this is really cool and it's fun now if we flip back to the slides here.
Let's go to the next slide so what I want to do is introduce you to the inception
framework.
We have been working on this code for about nine months evolving it
as it goes forward and within the next month we will be releasing a reference
app that allows you to build solutions like this using a connect
sensor and all the measure plumbing we will shipped to you
connect telemetry capture routine that knows how to talk to connect and deliver
the telemetry efficiently of the any see plug-in that
allows us to augment and extend that data from the connect censor the as
your scripps by the way that asher our script right there is well worth the price of admission by
itself all right that bad boys about a hundred-and-fifty beautiful...our
shell all right the automate everything just give us a subscription number and we're off
will give you a kiosk reference app that will allow you to do some of these basic interactions and
off you go...give you a biometric in face recognition app what that is all
about is the ability to understand how we're doing the biometric and face so you could say, you know,
what I don't want your kiosk thing man I want to do something cooler
weather let me just see how you made that all happened and then ultimately we're
going to give you are basic object detection code so that you can understand when people are
grabbing and touching objects in a physical space that's cool right?
...great all right let's go to the next slide...
So, go...inception in combination with windows ten
...you do amazing things now why do I mention windows
...I was running inception on windows eight here.
Windows ten gives me an
entirely new pivot because I now have a computer framework that
...understands where you are who you are I can
do voice recognition on windows eight but it's dictation engine if...of that
...I want to do keywords spotting I want to
do continuous recognition if I'm in a space I want to recognize
me and I wanted to understand...is an expert in all things connect if
todd starts talking connect I wanted to go retrieve information
forming windows ten gives me that extensibility that I need to deliver
that if it on the foundation ultimately sign up for
inception stop by the connect booth out here all be hanging out...I'll get you on
...line when we...when we formally release it will be on the connect blog to let, you know,
when to get and ultimately guys go do cool an amazing things
...I watchdog thank you thank you?
All right so we saw a little bit of a rainbow
...from scenarios and to me the important part
...all of those directly.
Connect to scenarios for
...seeing really companies having real problems
...want to be solved so that's one important reason that we put
half of time in that basket and I hope you enjoy that so,
now we would like to go and zoom in a little bit on stream analytics and tell you
some more about that and what we as kind of approached we can go
and say among all those scenarios we are seeing effectively three?
...more but right now we...of focusing on three classes of scenarios the
first one is you want to capture streaming events as they come in
perhaps to some level of immediate cleansing filtering correlation with reference data
what not and archive so you can then later goal and do
it after the fact analysis so one example we solve that was after the fact I
would like to understand how plan production evolved over six months?
Second one dashboard ing I want
to go and see in many different ways what's happening
right now not just at the level of raw events but at the level of meaningful role
...of that I want to see various forms of aggregation over my data as it
happens and the third one is I want to actually cost activity
or action to happen if certain conditions are met I want to trigger workflows error cry
and may want to go and trigger the automatic shipping of new
sensors to their customers very much now being in the same business ...print
companies except a small company like error crime would never been able to do
that on the on deploying data centers around the globe building the logistics connections so on.
So, the way we typically build those solutions.
Is very kind of canonical and we actually saw in both of our
...presentations
essentially this pattern here where we start with a
form of raw data coming in getting collected sometimes
...gateways sometimes coming directly from the device typically going through event
Event...having this interesting property...retains incoming data
for short window like typically a day you can pay for more but, every
...have will keep data at least four-day which means that everything compost downstream from
their including stream analytics has an opportunity to recover from all sorts
of failures by simply quickly going back in time and replying.
The next step typically if you want to go down the real
time as it happens path ...use stream
analytics or other stream processing solutions that pulled from event
hap apply immediate processing and push the results
forward one thing that we saw repeatedly
is pushing forward into dashboards like our by.
We have a number of those cases we'll see another example of the later another
thing that we are only announcing today is and we'll see more
details about that later is where we're now integrating stream analytics and
...which will allow you to on-the-fly
...apply various interesting algorithms if
you like to the data that flies through the stream processor.
if you want to see what stream analytics brings in terms of advantages because,
you know,
to be fair the as a...spectrum of stream processing technologies
out there and many of them are in the space of fully general
programming frameworks there's like storm spock streaming many
of them and many of them run today on asher so you have the choice
so we want to code go over what are the kind of hard facts
that differentiate stream analytics from other solutions not in the sense of
this is better than that but in the sense of if you have to make that choice here's how you can think about that.
So, the first one is.
If you built and...is actually very...experience we have
hat with our many sort-of partners...working with your building extreme analytics
solution you have a here and now need.
That is often surprisingly low we scaled down to one megabyte
...second and make you pay for only that because it turns out that
is...six-point-four gigabytes
...that actually is for many solutions plenty.
But, of course you can and
...half both the ambition and the reality of scaling way up so we want to scaled
use solutions app to the gigabyte a second range.
We want to process
at low latency we're not actually processing at kind of
hard realtime latency we typically aim for kind of a single digits
seconds of the system is built to adapt automatically if you actually relative
to the resources seo paying for sending a relatively low
...of events then will automatically give you much better latency
okay so the system smartly adapts to
loadthe next kind of differentiating property is what is very
capable of correlating both between streams of data even
correlating and we'll see examples of that correlating events on a single stream of data
asking for happens before happens after I kind of scenarios but,
it also can correlate with reference data and we'll talk about that little bit later?
Ultimately it's a fully managed casual service so you get all the advantages of that is just kind of
kind of comes with the deal off as a services
likewise in the space of reliability we guarantee event delivery.
And, we guarantee business continuity.
Both things but if you build on
...infrastructure are actually very expensive for you
to maintain yourselves interesting property we sub-part effective audits
it for your own solution you need to be able to demonstrate security
...privacy properties to your auditor than having a piece in the middle that is
very-high-level makes it almost a self-evident situation you selected
Presley identifying data is gone there's no way
that someone can sneak some code somewhere...the solution that brings it back.
So, having the ability to audit for...properties of the system
is actually a key thing in more and more industries we...we talked about scale already?
And, finally let me not spend time on this right here we have done quite a bit
of work to make sure that you can very rapidly build a solutions by focusing
on the actual problem you're trying to solve instead of a lot of infrastructure aspects.
Historically you would have come and said I need to serve procure and
setup infrastructure this maybe as simple as getting some of the m
...the...you need to...solution you need
to goal and integrate with a lot of other things.
You need to manage the resilience...of your solution
easy goal and worry about scaling and ultimately you need to
monitor and troubleshooting solution so our aim is
to take most of that out of your hence do it for you and allow you to focus
on what you really want to do rather than this traditional stack of
...that...also have to do.
...here's just a very quick look the through malaise query language is
a fair subset of t sequel enriched with
a few temporal concepts and that's actually very important if you think about the
operators in sql
then almost all of them have this problem that I mention in the very beginning when you columns
...cass on the highway almost all of them would never give you an answer on an infinite
stream so the temporally extensions are absolutely vital to make this kind of language work?
So, this point eye-hand back to depends on clements.
So, we have heard enough about this product we have seen a lot of examples
now let's get a little deeper into the language and see how you can do things and, what it
...let's take the scenario let's say media a website company they want to increase traffic to their
website and they are trying to look for trends tapping into social media they want to look
for what are the trending topics which topics having more
...and based on that big decisions right so here is
we tapping into like through the stream and the payload looks something like this we have a time
stamp we have the user who is threading the text what...the time zones etc?
If I have this twitter stream and I want to say thatshow me the
user name and the...a particular topics
xbox how would I write that now consider here...is a
moving towards the right the time flows towards the right and we're all familiar with a sequel
statements it...just as simple as you had been using it so I use a
select here I use that username the time zone from the incoming stream and where
...restricts box
right now let's see how that would look like if I want to really experience this in the
...portal...that would look like this switch?
Okay, so, I'm a...right now and let me quickly when create a job and
we can see here on the data services you see stream analytics values quick create ansi.
Mining.
Build job and I can select the region here.
Where I wanted to create selected us central and now
what is doing is it's trying to create a shell form?
So, the
job the shell has been created but that has nothing yet and.
Having a job operational really is a matter of
few steps the first thing you do is you have to add input meaning describing
whether data is coming from so let's say I...add an input we support data
streams and reference data clemens we'll talk about that a little later so I
select data streams and let's mit data is coming from event up...name here.
Input stream and this is the name how you
refereed in the query I could actually.
Map it to something that exist in...
In my subscription and it...put all
the details for me you can see it has event up here I selected the name space of service
...and it shows me which event of it is I
go to next and I can select what's relation format my...coming in this case it's just
...format I see okay now it has created added that and it's also being a
sanity check whether this particular sources available on not even if it's not then
...still allow you to go ahead and create the job you need to make sure that
at runtime this sources available so I have got my
input created I go to output and I can add another output
the these are the outputs that we support the our via is now in
preview so let's try that out so I can go to our by first thing it will ask you
is to entrees once you get authorized you can go ahead and name.
Give you give it a name so I named it output.
My dataset...table name.
I have my input created I have my output created now the next thing is I have to go
...right my query.
So, let's take the example that
we just saw I'll go ahead and the powerpoint slide deck and just copy that query.
And, put it here now.
Normally a good developer experience is you want to validate how your
query the query that your...whether it is correct or not normally in a streaming data is
very difficult because you have tons of data flowing at you and you're running a query whatever you a
seeing in the output maybe right or maybe not how do you make sure that you have written the correct query and
make changes according to you need a good way would be to take a sample
data and test over that so we have does button here that allows you to map it to
...local fights you can actually grab data from your incoming sources
there and, then map it to of file here I have some data collected?
I run the query against that and I can see the results right there in my browser if I want to make changes,
for example, let me add the time stamped here.
And, just to ...and now have the time
stamp also coming up so this allows me a nice way to see what the
results are and give me the opportunity to make changes and then I can deploy the job.
Okay, so, that was good now let's.
Look, at some more examples.
We're doing isvery common concept for streaming so you want to ask questions
not like select start off everything that was good for the database world but now select star
of everything means you have to define what that everything means and that should be within
a windows as clemens
...saying ifcarson moving over a highly than you may say given the count of
cars overlaps one our five minutes or one-minute so we support three kinds of windows
doubling windows hopping window and sliding
window all windows are fixed length and they are supported by the group biker.
Now in this example you can see window one has a few event that fall within
it space if I want to do aggregations like some
...count that the result would be shown at the end of the
windows and all events in streamant takes has a
...associated with it so the output that we see will also have a...stem but it will be
aligned to the end of the window.
let's take this example of...helping windows hopping window...
I may want to define like give-me account within a ten second timeframe now
I may want to see results more quickly I want to see
results every one second or every five-second show me the result of the last ten seconds so
here's an example if I want to give me what is
account of tweets over the last ten seconds how do I write that query
it's very simple but I wanted to be updated every five seconds so you just use of function
call hopping window give it a parameter...parameter stan and five.
And, there you go now imagine if you have to write such code it
would be tough because you have to do state management and various other things to make sure you're doing the right thing.
Another a useful thing is how do I
correlate data together let's take this example
I have the twitter stream coming in and the second one
in the green is the same stream but it's forward in time if I want to see
all the users of a particular topic that the...on a particular topic if that
switch this sentiment within one-minute these are some kind of
pattern analyses that you're trying to do how do I write that.
If you look at that query.
I have a from.
...stream which is my first stream.
And, then join it to the same stream and bring a kind of a says join there and I am
joining on not every join its...have a condition right so here my condition is the
user needs to be same and the topic needs to be seems the same user
is reading on the same topic but the sentiment has changed so that I have in the
...class if the sentiment of the first one is not equal sentiment of the
second one but there is one thing interesting that to observe normally in
sql just that kind of joins the condition will work but this is streaming so there has to be a
bound time bound this join condition is valid
between one-minute that's what I want the results for so if I run this query
I will see the green once the pairs would be coming in my output but the
red one suddenly meets the join condition but the difference of
time is more than one-minute so that doesn't...so the correlation of time automatically happens.
Another interesting thing is
to detect absence of something how do I do that, for example,
if I want to find out if a particular topic was not being treated for the last
ten seconds how do I do that it's very simple I use the leftover join.
And, on my...stream I compare it to...
So, these are very well-known tactics and you can apply your same scales
in the stream antics query language and build different patterns very easily.
Ok, so, that's the one thing that get left out because that was not...
...to talk about the reference data is switch over to clements.
Shows and I think we'll go a little faster now because we're approaching the end of
So, I already mentioned that besides joining between
streams we can join with reference data
there's a little sort of trick to that and that is understanding that these
...analytics engine.
At runtime can time travel
...backwards both to meet join requests like
joined twitter now...twitter at some earlier point in time or
to recover from internal failures and therefore we cannot actually use
the typical mutable store like a database of for reference data
so instead we drawn reference data out of blob store but,
do support the notion that you periodically push
updated reference data into...star was a time stamp so we can then
go and say which of those snapshots we should use when
...against reference data that is actually a very powerful technique
in the rt space because most devices send you some cryptic...
That aren't suitable for further processing...you want to join them you get an device
at the want to join it against a device logical name you get an ip address you wanted to
...against a geo location so, on.
All right very quickly on this one the entire
from analytics engine is builds to half absolutely zero centralize
...all centralize coordination
...fully distributed execution framework and that means if you only give us
enough information about how your data is partitions and how your query naturally
partitions we can give you whatever scale underlying hardware can give you?
So, the trick here really is to just tell us that
a particular stream is partitioned by the way all data coming from event have if you use
event...in a normal form is already partitioned by the
partitions sharks of the event up so they ask you first?
Opportunity and then you can ask us to read partition your data for various purposes or you can do
reduce style things are first doing in parallel operations
over the partitions and then reducing to a global result.
So, here's an example of more complex query that uses a number
of these techniques...uses the sequel concept of common table
...functional languages people call that a let lift so,
these with expressions are basically having
some queries we interpret top-level with as you telling us that there's
a natural step nature do a query.
And, if appropriate we use...to build a pipeline
...time instead of running everything on a single node so we do
...out and pipelining three-dimensional optimization for your queries.
...the one thing I definitely want to make sure we squeeze into
...I already mentioned briefly.
As of today we are in a ltd preview
with our ml integration so if you interested in that are team
block it's not quite up yet so perhaps check tomorrow our team
...will have information about how to sign up for that
limited preview and we asked for a description of the scenario
we have in mind because we want to actually goal with the selected initial
partners in that preview and,
really understand what works what doesn't work what's missing so,
that's this and the model for that
is extremely simple hiya is the case where you want to apply?
Function really user-defined function to every point.
Every data point on a stream and you may have noticed stream
...itself doesn't have any user-defined functions at least...say my god that's a huge
...the ml integration back
...because in the and xml can run arbitrary code
today in our python in the future and other languages so,
you just bind...arbitrary rest endpoint that has the right kind of
protocol support to a function name and in this case it happens to be an
operation list ml model and we do have a demo for this.
Sources switch back to.
Yeah, that's switch back and after that we'll close...session I'll just give you a little bit of detail on
the pricing of stream analytics as a service so here we have a
...dashboard and you can see we can see the trend here the count of
...by topic I am looking for some interesting topics like is your microsoft
seattle and various other things on my right I can see what are the text that are coming in
...cool things like how many total count of creates and I can also see the sentiments along with
each text so let's take a look at how this is possible what's going on
behind-the-scene so let me switch to.
The job.
So, here's the job that is running and where you see that dashboard I'm making a
call sentiment which is a function that have define this is pointing to an animal model
clemens says and that's all you do so every for every
event that comes in here I'm calling a sentiment model you can
use animal diction or any other thing that is supported in machine learning and...to that so
...also shows how you can take the output off...query which
...to a particular output...and take the rest of them and push to a different one
...support basically multiple outputs
here is how the monitoring dashboard will look like and I can see how many events
are flowing in what is a kind of output I'll be seeing whether...were in
...runtime terror not so this gives me a very nice view of what's going on with my system?
And,...set the one thing
I want to quickly talk about is pricing we found out that
they're really two reasons that good pricing of
that particular services relevant one is that some people care about massive scale-up
...we have actually found far more people care about is running a potentially very large number of
...streaming jobs
in the larger complex environment so we drove this
...quite way down to give you an idea we're measuring two things one is
the actual volume of data process at one-tenth of a sense per
cent for gigabyte process and the other one is a blended unit
...compute resourcescourse memory and
bandwidth and, three-point-one sense per hour.
Ok, and, that translates into the smallest
single streaming unit job running non-stop costing you just a little
the under twenty five dollars a month that's thirty.
Right and that...you will actually find to be really difficult
to pay for vm resources yourself to get anywhere close to that price.
And, we do a little more than just give you the m ok so that's the pricing.
I think we don't actually have official time for questions but I would still like
you to take the opportunity if you have questions where some microphones here.
Do this one yes?